<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Some assemblage required</title>
    <link>http://djon.es/blog</link>
    <description>Some assemblage required - a blog about learning, teaching and technology</description>
    <atom:link href="http://djon.es/blog" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en-AU</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 12:05:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>What are the impediments to quality teaching and what can be done to remove them?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is something I wrote in a protected post years ago. I want to get this bit out in the open.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/05/30/what-are-the-impediments-to-quality-teaching-and-what-can-be-done-to-remove-them/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/05/30/what-are-the-impediments-to-quality-teaching-and-what-can-be-done-to-remove-them/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding (digital) education through workarounds and quality indicators</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 and the subsequent #pivotonline has higher education paying a lot more attention to the use of digital and online technology for learning and teaching (digital education). COVID-19 has made digital education necessary. COVID-19 has made any form of education – and just about anything else – more difficult. For everyone. COVID-19 and it’s impact is rewriting what higher education will be after. COVID-19 is raising hopes and fears that what will come after will be (positively?) transformative. Not beholden to previous conceptions and corporate mores.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/06/02/understanding-digital-education-through-workarounds-and-quality-indicators/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/06/02/understanding-digital-education-through-workarounds-and-quality-indicators/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing a personal "memex" with Foam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designing potential use of Foam for PKM&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/07/06/designing-a-personal-memex-with-foam/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/07/06/designing-a-personal-memex-with-foam/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with memex</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My last post was an exploration of Foam (a nascent personal knowledge management and sharing system) and how I might use it. This post documents two steps toward implementation&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/07/07/getting-started-with-memex/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/07/07/getting-started-with-memex/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pondering if and how Hax &amp; web components fit in Blackboard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add the "magic script" to my Wordpress install and we have...&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/01/pondering-if-and-how-hax-web-components-fit-in-blackboard/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/01/pondering-if-and-how-hax-web-components-fit-in-blackboard/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualising and pruning my Memex</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In writing the following I stumbled across the idea that writing blog posts in Foam would enable the merging of content from Memex and blog posts. I then discovered it didn't work out of the box. More work was needed. But the nature of the technology involved meant that it wasn't that hard and is now complete. You'll see links below followed by the spider web emoji (🕸️), those are links to my Memex. Meaning I this bit of bricolage can be linked to my Memex's page on Bricolage. It's this type of capability that might address the Reusability Paradox in digital learning technology, but more on that soon.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/09/visualising-and-pruning-my-memex/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/09/visualising-and-pruning-my-memex/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting the design of discipline-specific digital learning activities</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It's widely accepted that the most important part of learning and teaching is what the student does (Biggs, 2012). The spaces, tools and tasks in and through which students "do stuff" (i.e. learning, or not) are in some way designed by a teacher with subsequent learner adaptation (Goodyear, 2020).&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/15/supporting-the-design-of-discipline-specific-digital-learning-activities/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/08/15/supporting-the-design-of-discipline-specific-digital-learning-activities/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on "How learning design systems can help scale and accelerate learning design"</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 30 I watched a webinar (recording below) given by Joyce Seitzinger (@catspyjamasnz) and hosted by the Commonwealth of Learning. It was titled, "How Learning Design Systems can help scale and accelerate learning design". If you work in higher education helping with the practice of digital (or post-digital education) - which is a bigger group of folk than it was 12 months ago - then I recommend the talk and the approach. Especially, if you're having to deal with scale - large student numbers, large numbers of courses, multiple offerings etc.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2020/11/16/reflections-on-how-learning-design-systems-can-help-scale-and-accelerate-learning-design/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2020/11/16/reflections-on-how-learning-design-systems-can-help-scale-and-accelerate-learning-design/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the little things matter in design for learning?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In learning what matters most is what the learner does. As people looking to help people learn we can't make them learn. The best we can do is to create learning situations - see Goodyear, Carvalho &amp; Yeoman (2021) for why I'm using situation and not environment. We design the task, the learning space and social organisation (alone, pairs, groups etc.) that make up the situation in which they will engage in some activity. Hopefully activity that will lead to the learning outcomes we had in mind when designing the situation.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/06/do-the-little-things-matter-in-design-for-learning/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/06/do-the-little-things-matter-in-design-for-learning/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the spread of the Card Interface for Blackboard Learn</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2018 I started work at an institution using Blackboard Learn. My first project helping "put online" a group of 7 courses highlighted just how ugly Blackboard sites could be and how hard it was to do anything about it. By January 2019 I shared the solution I'd developed - the Card Interface. Below is a before/after image illustrating how the Card Interface 'tweaks' a standard Blackboard Learn content area into something more visual and contemporary. To do this you add some provided Javascript to the page and then add some card meta data to the other items.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/12/reflecting-on-the-spread-of-the-card-interface-for-blackboard-learn/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/12/reflecting-on-the-spread-of-the-card-interface-for-blackboard-learn/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the symbols in digital education/design for learning?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Benbya et al (2020, p. 3) argue that digitial technologies do make a difference, including this point (among others)&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/24/what-are-the-symbols-in-digital-education-design-for-learning/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/24/what-are-the-symbols-in-digital-education-design-for-learning/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On formal qualifications and improving learning and teaching</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is sparked by Twitter conversations arising from a tweet from @neilmosley5 quoting from this article by Tony Bates. In particular, pondering a tweet from @gamerlearner where the idea is that a "consistent requirement for educators in HE to have some kind of formal teaching qual" will not only help motivate academics "to take time out to learn how to teach better" and generally value teaching more.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/30/on-formal-qualifications-and-improving-learning-and-teaching/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/03/30/on-formal-qualifications-and-improving-learning-and-teaching/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Dron's definition of educational technology</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pre-COVID the role of technology in learning and teaching in higher education was important. However, in 2020 it became core as part of the COVID response. Given the circumstances it is no surprise that chunks of that response were not that great. There was some good work. There was a lot of a "good enough for the situation" work. There was quite a bit that really sucked. For example,&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/06/04/exploring-drons-definition-of-educational-technology/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/06/04/exploring-drons-definition-of-educational-technology/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representing problems to make the solution transparent</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following illustrates how the game Number Scrabble and Herb Simon's thoughts on the importance of design representation appears likely to help with migration of 1000s of course sites from Blackboard Learn (aka Blackboard Original) to another LMS. Not to mention becoming useful post-migration.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2021/10/23/representing-problems-to-make-the-solution-transparent/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2021/10/23/representing-problems-to-make-the-solution-transparent/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrating entangled relations to break the iron triangle: examples from a LMS migration</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All university strategies for learning and teaching seek to maximise: accessibility (as many people as possible can participate - feel the scale - in as many ways as possible); quality (it's good); and, cost effectiveness (it's cheap to produce and offer). Ryan et al (2021) argue that this is a "key issue for contemporary higher education" (p. 1383) due to inevitable cost constraints, the benefits of increased access to higher education, and requirements to maintain quality standards. However, the literature on the "iron triangle" in higher education (e.g. Daniel et al, 2009; Mulder, 2013; Ryan et al, 2021) suggests that maximising all three is difficult, if not impossible. As illustrated in Figure 1 (adapted from Mulder, 2013, p. 100) the iron triangle suggests that changes in one (e.g. changing accessibility from on-campus to online due to COVID) will have negatively impact at least one, but probably both, of the other qualities (e.g. the COVID response involving increase in workload for staff and resulting in less than happy participants).&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2022/07/05/orchestrating-entangled-relations-to-break-the-iron-triangle-examples-from-a-lms-migration/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2022/07/05/orchestrating-entangled-relations-to-break-the-iron-triangle-examples-from-a-lms-migration/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrating entangled relations to stretch the iron triangle: Observations from an LMS migration</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work arose from the depths of an institutional LMS migration (Blackboard Learn to Canvas). In particular, the observation that the default migration processes required an awful lot of low level manual labour. Methods that appeared to reduce the quality of the migration process and increase the cost. Hence we started developing different methods. As the migration project unfolded we kept developing and refining. Building on what we'd done before and further decreasing the cost of migration, increasing the quality of the end result, and increasing the scale and diversity of what we could migrate.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2022/10/10/orchestrating-entangled-relations-to-stretch-the-iron-triangle-observations-from-an-lms-migration/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2022/10/10/orchestrating-entangled-relations-to-stretch-the-iron-triangle-observations-from-an-lms-migration/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gatherers, Weavers and Augmenters: Three principles for dynamic and sustainable delivery of quality learning and teaching</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Henry Cook, Steven Booten and I gave the following presentation at the THETA conference in Brisbane in April 2023.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2023/02/09/gathers-weavers-and-augmenters-three-principles-for-dynamic-and-sustainable-delivery-of-quality-learning-and-teaching/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2023/02/09/gathers-weavers-and-augmenters-three-principles-for-dynamic-and-sustainable-delivery-of-quality-learning-and-teaching/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higher ed L&amp;T's scale problem?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contemporary higher education appears to have a scale problem.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2023/02/23/higher-ed-lts-scale-problem/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2023/02/23/higher-ed-lts-scale-problem/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing (finally) Canvas Collections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, a reasonable version of Canvas Collections and associated support materials is ready to announce. Following will eventually form the content of a blog post posted to the Canvas community space.&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2023/08/18/announcing-finally-canvas-collections/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2023/08/18/announcing-finally-canvas-collections/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What now?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024 passed without a post to this blog. Many reasons, but largely because I moved on from higher education. Suddenly digital education - the old focus of this blog - wasn't a big part of my thinking. Raising the question, what now?&lt;a href="https://djon.es/blog2/2025/01/12/what-now/"&gt;...more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://djon.es/blog2/2025/01/12/what-now/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
